A Guide to the Papers of the Albemarle County Medical Society, 1933-2002
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
The Papers of the Albemarle County Medical Society 1933-2002
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-29
14 boxes 5"x10.5"x15.5", 6 linear feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by the Albemarle County Medical Society.
Biographical Information
The Seal of the Albemarle County Medical Society (ACMS) indicates that it was organized in 1914, but Dr. Armistead Page Booker who wrote an unfinished draft of the history of the society postulated that it may have existed as early as 1851. He quotes Dr. Wyndham Blanton in "Medicine in Virginia in the Nineteenth Century" as noting, "in January 1851, the 'Stethoscope,' a medical journal of that time, reported that there was a local society in Charlottesville." Booker's draft continues to trace the early days and states, "in the first published list of the component [local] societies, in the 22 January 1915 issue of the 'Virginia Medical Semi-Monthly,' there is the 'Doctors' Club' with Dr. J. Carroll Flippin as President and Dr. Halstead S. Hedges as Secretary. In October 1915, in the 'Transactions,' there is a listing of the component state societies, by congressional districts, as well as the names and places of residence of all of the members. The only local society included, the 'Albemarle County Society,' had 38 members." By 1925 membership had grown to 79 active members. In 1950 there were 131 and by 1982 the number reached 475. Booker points out that many members distinguished themselves over the years as teachers, practitioners, original thinkers in clinical and basic research, and leaders in organized medicine.
The Society has served as an arena for scientific talks and socializing as well as a forum for legislative information and action and community service. The Society was the driving force behind the mass oral polio virus vaccinations that were given in the Charlottesville area in the early 1960s. The Society weighed in on fluoridation of the Charlottesville water supply, health care of the elderly, medical malpractice, driving under the influence, and seat belts, and has lobbied state and national representatives concerning medically related legislation. That lobbying has resulted in letters from Lyndon B. Johnson, John F. Kennedy, Harry F. Byrd, Thomas J. Michie, Virginius Dabney, and Huburt H. Humphrey among others.
The "Albemarle Medical News" has been published by the ACMS since Spring 1992. Originally a quarterly, it is now published twice a year. It includes medical articles of interest, legislative updates, memoriams for members, and medical students news. Its inaugural issue states that there are nearly 500 physicians (almost evenly divided between University physicians and physicians in private practice) who are members of the ACMS and that it is a component of the Medical Society of Virginia. The "Message from the President" goes on to say, "Our business is communication. Our monthly meeting is almost like the old town meeting where everyone gets brought up to date on the latest developments in medicine and then gets a chance to give feedback. We discuss local medical problems and help find solutions to them. At each meeting we have a scientific presentation of broad clinical interest. After the business and the scientific portions of the meeting we have a reception and dinner together."
Over the years the Society has financially supported various entities including the American Medical Education Fund, the Medical Student Scholarship Fund, the local rescue squads, the Bessie Dunn Miller Cancer Center, and the Virginia Council on Health and Medical Care.
Scope and Content
The collection includes five boxes of membership applications; four boxes of subject-related files, including committee papers, the government and bylaws of ACMS, resolutions passed, and the women's auxiliary; one box of minutes from years 1951 to 2001; one box of correspondence from 1948-2002; and three boxes of financial records beginning in 1933. There is one photograph of nineteen of the presidents of the ACMS taken in 1981.
Arrangement
Boxes 1-5 are arranged alphabetically by the last names of the membership applicants, boxes 6-9 are arranged alphabetically by subject, and boxes 10-14 are arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Membership applications and related documents 1948-98, 29 D, 37pp. (Box-folder 01-001)
  Abdel-Rahman, Emaad; Abel, Mark Francis; Abse, David Wilfred; Adams, Jimmy Wayne; Adams, Reid B.; Adamson, Nathaniel Edward; Ajgaonkar, Ashok Dinakar; Albert, Martin Philip; Aldrich, C. Knight
- Membership applications and related documents 1950-2000, 42 D, 68pp. (Box-folder 01-002)
  Alexander, Burton F.; Alexander, Haddon Christopher; Alford, Bennett A.; Allan, John Hamilton; Allen, Miller Shannon; Allen, Robert C.; Aller, James David
- Membership applications and related documents 1950-97, 38 D, 43pp. (Box-folder 01-003)
  Andrews, James Claire; Andrews, Katherine patricia McGinnis; Angello, Debra Ann; Archer, Harry L.; Arnold, Michael L.; Arnold, William Percy; Arora, Narinder Singh; Ashby, Finlay Michael; Ashley, John Thomas; Askew, Fletcher C.; Atuk, Nuzhet Osman; Ayers, Carlos R.
- Membership applications and related documents 1977-2000, 24 D, 49pp. (Box-folder 01-004)
  Bailey, Andrew Allison; Bailey, C. Cabell; Balukar, David H.; Barnett, Benjamin Lewis; Bateman, Bruce G.; Battig, Charles G.; Becker, Daniel M.; Beller, George A.; Bender, Arthur S.
- Membership applications and related documents 1966-2001, 20 D, 63pp. (Box-folder 01-005)
  Bernstein, Richard Carl; Berry, Frederic Aroyce; Bickson, Stephen J.; Blackman, James A.; Blaine, David A.; Blandenbaker, Walter Linwood; Bleck, Thomas P.; Blizzard, Robert Martin; Blommel, Julie L.
- Membership applications and related documents 1973-98, 17 D, 34 pp. (Box-folder 01-006)
  Bogdonoff, David Leonard; Bolton, Warren Kline; Bond, G Randall; Bono, Joseph A.; Bourgeois, Francis John; Boyle, Robert John; Bradley, Robert James; Braithwaite, Sabina A.; Brashear, H. Robert
- Membership applications and related documents 1947-2001, 26 D, 28pp. (Box-folder 01-007)
  Braun, Hans D.; Brenbridge, Norman A.G.; Brewer, Richard James; Bright, Richard Homer; Brooks, Sidney C.; Brown, Philip Manton; Brown, Robert Stanley; Brown, Jr., Robert Stanley; Bruce, James Garnett
- Membership applications and related documents 1950-2001, 23 D, 23pp. (Box-folder 01-008)
  Brunk, James Robert; Brunner, Carolyn M.; Bruns, David E.; Buckman, John; Burkholder, Burton V.; Burwell, Lawrence Rogers; Buschi, Anthony J.; Buxton, William Dimmock
- Membership applications and related documents 1976-2001, 15 D, 30pp. (Box-folder 01-009)
  Cail, Wayne S.; Caldwell, Stephen H.; Call, Robert Somerville; Campa, Justiniano F.; Campbell, Deborah L.; Canterbury, Randolph Jack; Cantrell, Robert Wendall; Capps, Gerald Wayne
- Membership applications and related documents 1951-98, 32 D, 33pp. (Box-folder 01-010)
  Caraway, David L.; Carey, Robert Munson; Carpenter, John M.; Carpenter, Martha Alma; Carter, Bruce Thomas;; Carter, William E.; Cates, Michael Aubrey; Caughron, Samuel D.; Cawley, Edward Philip; Chamberlain, Charles Richard; chan, donald P.K.
- Membership applications and related documents 1972-2000, 21 D, 34pp. (Box-folder 01-011)
  Chekan, Edward Gerald; Chenelle, Andrew George; Chesler, David Lawrence; Chevalier, Robert Louis; Clark, Pamela; Clarke, William Linus; Coates, Michael L.; Collins, Phil
- Membership applications and related documents 1946-99, 39 D, 53pp. (Box-folder 01-012)
  Combs, Luke; Cominelli, Fabio; Constable, William C.; Conway, Brian Peter; Cook, Robert Lewis; Cooper, George Marion; Corbett, Eugene; Cosgrove, Michael Joseph
- Membership applications and related documents 1952-97, 27 D, 36pp. (Box-folder 01-013)
  Craddock, George Barksdale; Craddock, William Edmund; Craig, James William; Crampton, Richard Savington; Crigler, F. Jason; Crow, Peter H.; Cullander, Cecil Carleton Helmer; Cumbia, Jesse Wesley
- Membership applications and related documents, Da-David 1943-96, 20 D, 27pp. (Box-folder 02-001)
  D'Alessandro, Frank Thomas; Dalldorf, Carolyn J.; Dalton, Claudette Harloe; Dandridge, William Robert; Daniel, Thomas Moore; David, Joseph Jordan
- Membership applications and related documents, Davis-Dem 1962-94, 15 D, 19pp. (Box-folder 02-002)
  Davis, Charles Monroe; Davis, Jeffrey Dean; Davis, IV, John Staige; Davis, Sheila F.; Dee, Paul M.; Degnan, Gregory Gerard; de Lange, Eduard E.; DeMarco, Paul Vincent
- Membership applications and related documents, Den-Di 1964-2001, 16 D, 21pp. (Box-folder 02-003)
  Densmore, Jeanne; Densmore, John J.; Derdeyn, Andre P.; DeSilvey, Dennis L.; Dickens, Michael Douglas; Diduch, David R.; DiFazio, Cosmo A.
- Membership applications and related documents, Do-Dz 1961-95, 20 D, 20pp. (Box-folder 02-004)
  Donowitz, Leigh Grossman; Doull, Gregory Harrison; Drake, David Bartleson; Dreifuss, Fritz Emanuel; Duani, David Simon; Dudley, Thomas H.; Dunn, John Thornton; Durbin, Charles G.; Dyer, Robert Kent
- Membership applications and related documents, E 1970-98, 23 D, 49pp. (Box-folder 02-005)
  Eastham, Rosser Jackson; Ebert, Eleanore M.; Edge, Stephen B.; Edgerton, Milton Thomas; Elbirlik, Kemal H.; Elward, Kurt; Engelhard, Carolyn Long; Epstein, Robert Marvin; Erickson, Brian L.
- Membership applications and related documents, F-Fl 1975-2000, 23 D, 26pp. (Box-folder 02-006)
  Fagerli, Julian Claus; Faidas, Anna; Farr, Barry Miller; Fechner, Robert Eugene; Fernbach, Louise O. Wensel; Finnerty, James J.; Fischer, Renee L.; Fletcher, John C.
- Membership applications and related documents, Fo-Fz 1954-94, 20 D, 21pp. (Box-folder 02-007)
  Foley, Eugene F.; Ford, Raymond Foust; Fortenberry, Frazier T.; Fox, Clifford H.; Freedman, William Bernis; Friend, Christopher D.; Fryburg, David Albert
- Membership applications and related documents, Ga-Gil 1948-2000, 26 D, 32pp. (Box-folder 02-008)
  Gal, Thomas Joseph; Gampper, Thomas J.; Gardella, Lynn; Garnett, Richard Wingfield; Garriss, George Waldon; Gay, Spencer B.; Generelly, Peter Robert; Gibson, Robert Stephen; Gillenwater, Jay Young
- Membership applications and related documents, Gim-Go 1960-2001, 16 D, 21pp. (Box-folder 02-009)
  Gimple, Lawrence W.; Giuliano, Vincent J.; Gleason, Charles Henry; Gomez, Diego A.; Gomez, Roberto Ariel; Gorsch, Stefan M.; Goss, Larry Zane
- Membership applications and related documents, Gr-Gz 1940-99, 20 D, 53pp. (Box-folder 02-010)
  Greenhoe, Joshua; Groschel, Dieter Hans Max; Grosh, William Wangerin; Gross, Charles Wayne; Guerrant, John L.; Guerrant, Richard Littleton; Gutgesell, Howard P.
- Membership applications and related documents, Ha-Han 1963-96, 14 D, 20pp. (Box-folder 02-011)
  Haden, James E.; Halapin, Philip Thomas; Haley, Elliott Clarke; Halseth, Michael J.; Hamill, Robin Jane; Hanks, John Bright; Hanna, George Russell; Hannan, Robert Laurence
- Membership applications and related documents, Hap-Hea 1953-2000, 17 D, 18pp. (Box-folder 02-012)
  Harbert, Guy Morley; Harlan, John; Harris, Mark M.; Harris, Ted Arthur; Harthun, Nancy; Haskins, Barbara Gay; Hawkes, David L; Hays, Richard B.; Heatwole, Kenneth M.
- Membership applications and related documents, Heb-Hend 1974-2000, 19 D, 33pp. (Box-folder 02-013)
  Hegarty, Thomas Joseph; Heil, Thomas; Heilbronner, David Mark; Heller, Jay Ronald; Helmly, Carolyn Sue Ridenour; Hendley, Joseph Owen; Hendrix, John David; Hendrix, Sylvia Sutton
- Membership applications and related documents, Hene-Hoo 1951-94, 19 D, 19pp. (Box-folder 02-014)
  Henry, Ann Katherine; Herring, Russell Edward; Hess, Charles Edwin; Hillman, Bruce J.; Hirschman, Henry; Hobbs, William R.; Hodge, Robert Henry; Hook, Edward Watson
- Membership applications and related documents, Hop-Hz 1955-97, 31 D, 34pp. (Box-folder 02-015)
  Horner, Walter Harry; Hostler, Sharon Lee; Howards, Stuart S.; Huber, Albert L.; Hucek, Andrew Michael; Huffman, John Christian; Humphries, John Elliott; Hunt, Charles F.; Hunter, Thomas H.; Hurwitz, Shepard
- Membership applications and related documents, I-Je 1961-95, 19 D, 30pp. (Box-folder 03-001)
  Jahrsdoerfer, Robert A.; Jane, John Anthony; Jeffries, William McKendree; Jenkins, Alan D.; Jennings, Robert Hutchings
- Membership applications and related documents, Ji-Jz 1954-88, 17 D, 27pp. (Box-folder 03-002)
  Johns, Dearing Ward; Johns, Roger A.; Johnson, Charles McCoy; Jones, Herbert Claiborne; Jones, Rayford Scott; Josephthal, Daniel
- Membership applications and related documents, Ka 1965-99, 17 D, 76pp. (Box-folder 03-003)
  Kahler, David M.; Kaltreider, Sara A.; Kassell, Neal Frederic; Kattwinkel, John; Katz, Martin D.; Kavanaugh, James Gibbonet
- Membership applications and related documents, Ke-Kim 1964-91, 19 D, 23pp. (Box-folder 03-004)
  Keats, Theodore E.; Kelly, Maria Denise; Kelly, Thaddeus Elliott; Kennan, James S.; Kenney, John Gale; Kern, John Allen; Kesler, Richard W.; Kim, Taik Chae
- Membership applications and related documents, Kin-Kz 1961-99, 24 D, 30pp. (Box-folder 03-005)
  Kitchin, James David; Knight, Donald Aubrey; Kondamuri, Shanu; Korbon, Gregg Allen; Kovac, Michael J.; Knasel, Anne Lowe; Kron, Irving L.; Krumholz, Alan Jay
- Membership applications and related documents, L-Lav 1974-96, 21 D, 26pp. (Box-folder 03-006)
  Lake, Carol L.; Lambert, Matthew J.; Lambert, Paul Ray; Lander, Christopher J.; Lanham, John Louis; Larner, James Mitchell; Lather, Ronald M.; Laviano, Trent
- Membership applications and related documents, Law-Lin 1961-93, 15 D, 35pp. (Box-folder 03-007)
  Lawson, Edgar Clifford; Leavell, Byrd Stuart; Lechner, Robert Bruce; Lee, Janet H.; Lee, Soo Ik; Lee, Thomas H.; Levine, Paul A.; Lindsay, Richard Walter
- Membership applications and related documents, Lio-Lz 1975-98, 14D, 30pp. (Box-folder 03-008)
  Lipper, Maurice H.; Lippert, Marguerite C.; Lobo, Monica Castelano; Lobo, Peter I.; Looney, William Boyd; Lowdon, J. Devon, Carl Lynch
- Membership applications and related documents, Ma-Mar 1947-97, 30 D, 56pp. (Box-folder 03-009)
  Machen, Charles William; MacIlwaine, William Andrew; MacIlwaine,IV, William Andrew; MacMillan, R. Hunt; Magee, Anna Mary; Mandell, Gerald; Marri, Ramalakshmi; Marshall, Hubert A.; Marshall, John C.; Martin; Marcus L.
- Membership applications and related documents, Mas-Math 1967-97, 12D, 49pp. (Box-folder 03-010)
  Masloff, James I.; Massaro, Thomas A.; Matherne, G. Paul; Mathew, Mammen M.
- Membership applications and related documents, Mati-McD 1959-2000, 14 D, 45pp. (Box-folder 03-011)
  Matsumoto, Alan H.; Maughan, Karen Lesley; May, Joseph Walton; McCue, Frank Cyrus; McCullough, Christopher S.; McDaniel, Nancy Lee
- Membership applications and related documents, Mce-Me 1947-97, 20 D, 27pp. (Box-folder 03-012)
  McGahren, Eugene; McGovern, John Joseph; McIlhenny, Joan; McLaughlin, David P.; McLaughlin, Robert E.; McLean, Walter Copley; McLeod, Susan Lee; Melton, Samuel Hughes; Meyer, G. Andrew
- Membership applications and related documents, Mi-Mon 1940-98, 38 D, 39pp. (Box-folder 03-013)
  Michel, Robert S.; Mika, David Bedrick; Miller, Charles W.; Miller James Quinter; Miller, Samuel Edmund; Minor, George Ridgeway; Moga, David Benjamin; Mohler, Daniel Nathan; Montgomery, Howard Arthur; Montgomery, Matthew T.
- Membership applications and related documents, Moo-Morr 1941-97, 32D, 36pp. (Box-folder 03-014)
  Moody, David T.; Moody, William Edward; Moon, Cary Nelson; Mooney, Joseph; Moore, Marcia Monroe; Morgan, Raymond F.; Morris, David Lyttelton; Morris, Jr., John Richard; Morris, III, John Richard
- Membership applications and related documents, Mors-Mz 1954-2000, 17 D, 22pp. (Box-folder 03-015)
  Morse, Robert Michael; Morton, Richard William; Mosca, Alfon Bernard; Muller, William Henry; Mullins, Darren E.; Munson, Amie Rinker; Murray, Latham B.; Murray, William Howard; Myers, Charles E.
- Membership applications and related documents, N 1968-99, 17 D, 24pp. (Box-folder 04-001)
  Nadkarni, Mohan; Nadler, Jerry Lee; Newman, Steven A.; Nolan, Stanton Peelle; Noonan, Daniel Joseph; Nordlund, John R.; Norwood, Victoria Fay
- Membership applications and related documents, O 1961-97, 20 D, 29pp. (Box-folder 04-002)
  Oblinger, Michael John; Okusa, Mark Douglas; Olsakovsky, Leslie A.; Ooghe, Robert Barksdale; Orlick, Joseph B.; Orr, William Allison; Ortiz, Edward Andrew; Owen, John Atkinson; Ozinal, Hasan Gungor; Ozinal, Ulku Sencer
- Membership applications and related documents, Pa-Pet 1970-2001, 19 D, 25pp. (Box-folder 04-003)
  Pambianco, Daniel John; Parlette, Harry Leslie; Paulsen, Elsa P.; Peake, Lilian Ruth; Pelton, Ernest William; Perriello, Vito Anthony; Peterson, Christine Marie
- Membership applications and related documents, Peu-Pop 1959-90, 26 D, 40pp. (Box-folder 04-004)
  Peura, David A.; Philbrick, John T.; Phillips, Lawrence Hamilton; Pietsch, Richard Lake; Platts-Mills, Thomas A. E.; Pollard, William Bryan; Popkin, Arnold B.
- Membership applications and related documents, Por-Pz 1976-98, 17 D, 28pp. (Box-folder 04-005)
  Post, Barbara T.; Post, John Hazen; Prillaman, Christina Wells; Prindle, Richard A.; Pritchard, Robert S.; Pruett, Timothy Lane; Prum, Bruce E.; Punyanitya, Voranoot
- Membership applications and related documents, Ra-Rh 1952-97, 17 D, 53pp. (Box-folder 04-006)
  Rabinowitz, Seymour; Reid, Robert Allen; Reynolds, David Nevin; Rein, Michael F.; Respess, James Cipriano; Reynolds, Robert Edgar; Rheuban, Karen S.; Rheuban, William Jay
- Membership applications and related documents, Ri-Rod 1966-2000, 23 D, 70pp. (Box-folder 04-007)
  Rice, Laurel Wysong; Rich, George Frederick; Rich, Tyvin; Richardson, Donald R.; Riddervold, Hans Olav; Riddick, George W.; Roberts, Robert J.; Rochester, Dudley Fortescue; Rodgers, Bradley M.
- Membership applications and related documents, Roe-Rz 1968-98, 20 D, 20pp. (Box-folder 04-008)
  Rogers, John F.; Rogol, Alan David; Rolen, Randall; Ross, William T.; Rowles, Billie Lamb; Rowlingson, John C.; Roy, Raymond Clyde; Rushia, Mary Ann; Rushia, Edwin L.
- Membership applications and related documents, Sa-Sche 1974-95, 16 D, 21pp. (Box-folder 04-009)
  Sansone, Philip Andrew; Santulli, Michael Edward; Sarembock, Ian Joseph; Saulsbury, Frank T.; Sawyer, Daniel W.; Sawyer, Russell Chandler; Schauer, Ashley H.; Scheld, W. Michael; Worthington, George Schenk
- Membership applications and related documents, Schi-Sea 1967-99, 18 D, 24pp. (Box-folder 04-010)
  Schildwachter, Thomas Legge; Schirmer, Bruce David; Schmitz, Stephen Earl; Schoeffel, Mark Edwin; Schorling, John; Schwenzer, Karen J.; Scoper, Stephen V.; Scott, James H.; Seale, Daniel Logan
- Membership applications and related documents, Seb-Sma 1951-95, 26D, 29pp. (Box-folder 04-011)
  Selden, Robert Francis; Shaffer, Hubert Adams; Shemo, Mary Carroll; Sheppe, William Marco; Shrum, John Richard; Shrum, Richard Coffman; Slingluff, Craig Lee; Smallwood, Harvey Daniel
- Membership applications and related documents, Sme-Sp 1951-97, 18 D, 20pp. (Box-folder 04-012)
  Smith, Deborah Elizabeth; Smith, Karl Daniel; Sommen, Lyn Van Der; Sommers, Linda M.; Spaulding, Cynthia Anne; Spence, George David; Spencer, Edward Monroe; Spotnitz, William David
- Membership applications and related documents, Sta-Sto 1963-95, 18 D, 27pp. (Box-folder 04-013)
  Stamp, Warren G.; Steers, William D.; Stevenson, William Cage; Stirt, Joseph A.; Stone, David Deaderick; Stone, David Joseph; Stone, James Walter
- Membership applications and related documents, Str-Sz 1955-92, 26 D, 26pp. (Box-folder 04-014)
  Straka, Bonnie Foster; Strasser, Heinz Jorg; Streicker, William F.; Strider, David Valentine; Stroud, Christopher B.; Sturgill, Benjamin Caleb; Suratt, Paul M.; Sutphen, James Leonard; Sweeney, Thomas Kevin; Sydnor, Thomas Austin
- Membership applications and related documents, Ta-Te 1954-99, 23 D, 30pp. (Box-folder 05-001)
  Talbott, William Gaines; Tatar, Steven Andrew; Taylor, Andrea Mestel; Taylor, Frank Eugene; Taylor, Peyton T.; Teates, Charles David; Tagmeyer, charles John; Teja, Jagdish S.
- Membership applications and related documents, Tha-Tho 1946-95, 32 D, 34pp. (Box-folder 05-002)
  Thiagarajah, Siva; Thibault, Alain; Thiele, Arthur L.; Thomson, James Anderson; Thorner, Michael Oliver; Thornsvard, Charles; Thornton, William Norman; Thorup, Oscar Andreas
- Membership applications and related documents, Thr-Tz 1967-2000, 25 D, 28pp. (Box-folder 05-003)
  Thurber, Charles F.; Tiedman, James Stuart; Tillack, Thomas Warner; Tompkins, Dorothy Guild; Tompkins, William Fraser; Tribble, Curtis Green; Turfboer, Robert; Turner, James C.; Turner, Ulysses (Jim) Grant
- Membership applications and related documents, U-V 1974-2001, 15 D, 17pp. (Box-folder 05-004)
  Underwood, Paul B., Van Slyke, K. Keller; Vance, Mary Lee; Vogel, Scott Durand
- Membership applications and related documents, Wa-Wei 1958-97, 19 D, 20pp. (Box-folder 05-005)
  Wallace, Karl Kenneth; Wallenborn, White McKenzie; Wang, Gwo-Jaw; Warren, Sarah Kathleen; Weary, Peyton Edwin; Weeks, Ruth Bley; Weinbaum, David L.; Weise, Kathryn Louise
- Membership applications and related documents, Wej-Wilk 1956-99, 21 D, 23pp. (Box-folder 05-006)
  Westerlund, Susan S.; Westervelt, Frederic Ballard; Wheby, Munsey Stephen; Whitehill, Richard; Whitworth, Claiborne Gooch; Wilhelm, Morton Callowhill; Wilkins, Paul Cole; Wilkowski, Deborah Ann W.
- Membership applications and related documents, Will-Wink 1966-97, 18 D, 24pp. (Box-folder 05-007)
  Williams, Gaylord Stone; Williams, Michael Eugene; Wills, Michael R.; Willson, Douglas F.; Wilson, Barbara Braunstein; Wilson, Edward Croft; Wilson, William Grady; Winkler, Charles Pincknay
- Membership applications and related documents, Wino-Wz 1959-97, 20 D, 22pp. (Box-folder 05-008)
  Winther, Birgit; Witmer, David S.; Wolanski, Edward T.; Wolpe, Joseph; Woodard, Robert Mason; Woods, Andrew Michael; Wotd, Benjamin H.; Woytowitz, Donald U.; Wyker, Arthur William
- Membership applications and related documents, X-Z 1967-95, 18 D, 19pp. (Box-folder 05-009)
  Youel, John Kenneth; Young, Jeffrey Seth; Younger, Deborah Anne; Zazakos, Christopher Peter
- Aetna life and disability insurance policies 1931-35, 18 D (Box-folder 06-001)
- American Medical Education Foundation 1959, 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 06-002)
- Blood Replacement Program 1956-60, 7 D (Box-folder 06-003)
- Book Memorial Program 1984-89, 14 D (Box-folder 06-004)
- Central Virginia Comprehensive Health Planning Council 1972, 6 D (Box-folder 06-005)
- Clean Indoor Air Ordinance 1987, 1989, 2 D (Box-folder 06-006)
- Committee Chairs and Members 1950-83, 39 D (Box-folder 06-007)
- Committee: Aging and Chronically Ill 1959-60, 5 D (Box-folder 06-008)
- Committee: Armed Services 1957-67, 3 D (Box-folder 06-009)
- Committee: Auditing 1971, 1 D (Box-folder 06-010)
- Committee: Bessie Dunn Miller Cancer Center 1945-67, 21 D (Box-folder 06-011)
- Committee: Medical Advisory Committee for the local Red Cross Blood Program 1952-67, 4 D (Box-folder 06-012)
- Committee: Membership 1967-87, 6 D (Box-folder 06-013)
- Committee: Nursing Home 1975, 3 D (Box-folder 06-014)
- Committee: Program 1948-70, 43 D (Box-folder 06-015)
- Committee: Public Health Advisory 1959-74, 7 D (Box-folder 06-016)
- Committee: Public Relations 1949-82, 67 D (Box-folder 06-017)
- Committee: Quality Health Care of the Elderly 1990-91, 6 D (Box-folder 06-018)
- Disaster Plan [1949-51], 2 D (Box-folder 06-019)
- Fluoridation of Charlottesville water supply 1950-59, 15 D (Box-folder 06-020)
- Government of ACMS: By-laws N.D., 4 D (Box-folder 07-001)
- Government of ACMS: Constitution pre 1945, 1 D (Box-folder 07-002)